# VENKATA PRASANT POODIPEDDI

## SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

## **CONTACT**



470.775.3512



<u>prasantvpoodipeddi@gmail</u>..com



Boulder, CO



<u>prasantdesigns.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/prasantpv</u>

## **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science in Applied Computer Science

Northwest Missouri State University, Maryville, MO | Dec 2017 GPA: 3.55/4.00

# Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

GITAM University, Visakhapatnam, India | May 2015 GPA: 7.86/10.00

#### SKILLS

**UX skills:** Visual design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Micro-interactions, Journey maps, Qualitative and Quantitative UX research, Interaction design, Usability testing, Storyboarding, Accessibility, Problem-solving, Agile methodology, Critical thinking, Heuristic evaluation, Branding, Front-end development **Tools:** Figma, Miro, Adobe XD, Sketch, Invision, Axure, Balsamiq, After Effects **Programming:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

IBM Design Thinking Co-creator (April 2022)

IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (March 2021)

#### **SUMMARY**

Seasoned **Product Designer** with **7 years** of experience in **diverse industries**, including health care, insurance, e-commerce, automotive, and IT, working in **B2B**, **B2C**, and **B2B2C** environments across enterprise and startup settings. A knack for **identifying edge cases** and delivering **visionary solutions** that enhance user experiences.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### HP Inc.

Senior Product Designer | Remote | October 2022 - Present

- Drive key features of Workforce Experience a B2B SaaS web app for IT
  admins in collaboration with product managers, developers, designers, UX
  researchers, and content writers to increase employee productivity
- Lead workshops on market analysis, edge cases, and feasibility
- Reduced 25% of ServiceNow incidents within 3 months and increased 15% customer base

#### **Ford Motor Company**

UX Designer | Dearborn, MI | April 2021 - August 2022

- Redesigned 'Performance Analytics for Connected Engineering' (PACE) a
   SaaS web app for internal engineers that monitors the Ford Connected
   Vehicle Ecosystem, by partnering with data scientists and product owners
- Reduced data visualization load time by 24%, decreased user time for major tasks by 23%, and boosted user base by 5x within 4 months of release

#### Humana

UX Designer | Louisville, KY | March 2018 - April 2021

- Redesigned Humana.com by creating an improved design system aligning with WCAG 2.1 guidelines in a cross-functional team. Achieved a remarkable 15% increase in returning Medicare and Medicaid users (~89,000) within 8 months
- Revamped the legacy B2B2C Agent Portal web app for insurance agents to streamline their key tasks incorporating the new brand guidelines. Reduced task completion time significantly by an average of 16%

#### **Senior World**

Creative Design Manager | Gurgaon, India | May 2015 - June 2016

- Designed an accessible B2C e-commerce website for senior citizens that features Consumer Electronics, Travel, and Health Care products
- Generated over 20,000 visits per day within a year